Grace McDonald Papers 5203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Grace McDonald Papers
1936-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
McDonald, Grace
5203
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Information on California Supreme Court, Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company vs. Public Utilities Commission and City of Los Angeles. California Supreme Court, Southern Pacific Company vs. Public Utilities Commission of the State of California. Copy of "Working Together - Our Priority", Annual report of Executive Secretary Grace McDonald. Papers include: Issues of Railroad Unity News, California Farm Reporter, "Swing Shift: A Novel" by Grace
5555879
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
HF, July 18, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Mrs. McDonald worked closely with her husband on the railroad unity movement of the 1930's. She organized the California Farmer-Labor Association and issued a monthly bulletin, Farmer Consumer Reporter. She also was a successful lobbyist and organizer on issues of small farmer welfare and labor cooperation.
Scope and Contents
Papers include: Issues of Railroad Unity News, California Farm Reporter, "Swing Shift: A Novel" by Grace McDonald.
Information on California Supreme Court, Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company vs. Public Utilities Commission and City of Los Angeles. California Supreme Court, Southern Pacific Company vs. Public Utilities Commission of the State of California. Copy of "Working Together - Our Priority", Annual report of Executive Secretary Grace McDonald.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Unemployment insurance; Social security; Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railroad Company.; Southern Pacific Company; United Transportation Union
5555879
- Railroad Unity News, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  11 issues, January-November 1936
- "The Railroad Monopoly-Public Enemy", 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  December 1950-January 1951
- California Farm Reporter. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Keep Railroads Safe", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Oct-48
- Reports death of J.E. McDonald, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  May-49
- "End Grade-Crossing Death-Traps", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Nov-49
- "R R Unions ask Farm Help;" "Fight to End Grade Crossings", 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  December 1949-January 1950
- "Grade Crossings Must Go", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Jun-50
- "Action to End RR Death Traps", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Sep-50
- "Railroads Evade Grade Crossing Liability", 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Jun-51
- "Court Rules Against Railroads", 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Dec-53
- "Transportation Policy Under Fire", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Jul-56
- Graham, Margaret (pseud. Grace Lois McDonald). Swing Shift: A Novel., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  The Citadel Press: New York, 1951. UTU Constitution, Article 92, p. 116, confirms rights of railroad employee to refuse to cross picket lines as described in the book.
- "Another Crossing Victim", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Jul-50
- California, Supreme Court, Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company vs. Public Utilities Commission and City of Los Angeles, Answer to Petition for Writ of Review. S.F. No. 18671 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- California, Supreme Court, Southern Pacific Company vs. Public Utilities Commission et al. Answer to Petition for Writ of Review. S.F. No. 18704., 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Writ denied, March 9, 1953. This action establishing RR liability for construction of grade crossings was invalidated by action of the state legislature setting a 10% limit on liability October 1, 1955. See Law of the State Legislature Chapter 1202 and Chapter 2091 of the Public Utility Code of 1957.
- U.S. Supreme Court, Southern Pacific Company vs. Public Utilities Commission of the State of California et al. Appeal., 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Statement in opposition to Appellant Statement. 1953-1954 Docket.
- "Working Together - Our Priority," Annual Report of Executive Secretary, Mrs. Grace McDonald, California Farmer Consumer Information Committee., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  June 21, 1969.